That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 7: Conqueror of Flames
（ケーニッヒ）ケ〜ッケッケッケ！
The great sorcerer Koenig has
come to pay his respects!
魔人ケーニッヒ様が
挨拶に来てやったぜ〜
Leon!
レオン！
I will defeat you and become
the Demon Lord myself!
貴様を倒して 俺様が魔王になる
安心して死ね！
You can die with your mind at ease!
（レオン）
小物が… 誰の差し金やら
Who sent a lowly creature like you here?
だが ちょうどいい
Still, this is a fine opportunity.
Your turn has come, Ifrit.
（レオン）出番だぞ
（シズ）え？
（レオン）イフリート
（レオン）どうした？
（シズ）あっ… え？
What's the matter?
（ケーニッヒ）
くう〜 ナメやがって！
俺様を無視するとは！
You're ignoring me?!
You'll regret underestimating me!
Oh, you want to die first?
先に死にたいのか？
いいだろう 死にやがれ！
Very well!
Go ahead and die!
フフ… これは面白い
Very interesting.
What did you say your name was?
（レオン）
お前の名前は何だったかな？
Shizu...e.
しず… え…
シズ… エ…
Shizu E?
Hm...
ふむ
今日より“シズ”と名乗るがいい
As of today, you will be called Shizu.
（シズ）シズ？
Shizu...
（ピリノ）
フフフ… たくさん食べてね
Eats lots, okay?
こっ この子
親と はぐれたみたいで…
I-It got separated from its mother...
P-Please pretend you didn't see this!
お… お願い 見逃して！
I won't tell anyone.
誰にも言わないよ
私も一緒に お世話していい？
Can I take care of it with you?
うん！　もちろん！
Yes, of course!
食べた 食べた！
He's eating!
わあ… ねえ この子の名前は？
So what's his name?
魔物に名前はないんだよ
Monsters don't have names.
But it's sad to have no name to go by.
（シズ）
名前がないのは かわいそうだよ
この子も そう言ってる
See? He agrees.
“ピズ”って どうかな？
How about Pizu?
Pizu... That sounds good!
ピズ… いいかも！
ねっ ピズ
Right, Pizu?
なんか大きくなった
Look! He got bigger!
ハハハ… 大きくなった！
You got bigger!
Pirino, you know you can't
take Pizu to the castle.
（シズ）
ピリノ ダメだよ
勝手に お城に連れてきちゃ
It'll be fine. He's really smart!
大丈夫だよ　この子 賢いし
But...
（シズ）でも…
He's really friendly with me.
（ピリノ）
こんなに懐いてるんだよ
使い魔として認めてくれるよ
I'm sure they'll let him be my familiar.
そうかな…
You think so?
（ピリノ）
あっ… どうしたの？　ピズ
What's wrong, Pizu?
It's okay... Come on, it's okay!
大丈夫だよ 大丈夫だから…
ねっ 落ち着いて
Just calm down!
Be good, now... Pizu!
いい子だから… ピズ！
It's okay... It's okay.
（ピリノ）大丈夫… 大丈夫だよ
シズ？
Shizu...
Enemy.
敵…
（ピリノ）いやあああ！
フン
What... did I just...
今… 何を…
M-My body...
かっ 体…
体が勝手に…
My body moved on its own...
炎で… 私は
The flames...
I... I...
私は… うっ…
ハア ハア…
うぐっ…
ハア…
（リムル）
俺たちの町
気に入ってもらえたかな？
So, do you like our town?
ええ とっても！
Yes, very much.
（リムル）
シズさんさえよかったら
いつまでだって いていいんだぞ
You're welcome to stay
as long as you'd like, Shizu-san.
（シズ）ありがとう
Thank you...
but I have to go.
でも… 行かなきゃ
You do?
（リムル）そっか
If I stay here, I might
bring trouble for you.
（シズ）
ここにいたら
迷惑をかけちゃうかもしれないし
私の旅の目的は…
The goal of my journey is...
Goal?
（リムル）目的？
（シズ）私を召喚した男を捜すこと
...to find the man who summoned me.
（リムル）
見つけたら どうするんだ？
What will you do when you find him?
Well, okay!
分かった！　残念だけど
いつでも遊びに来てくれ
It's too bad, but you can come visit anytime!
歓迎するよ
You'll always be welcome! Right, Ranga?
なっ ランガ
Of course!
（ランガ）もちろんです！
うん ありがとう
Okay. Thank you.
Thank you, too, Ranga.
ランガも ありがとう
（エレン）
シズさん
一緒にブルムンドに戻りません？
Shizu, why don't you come
back to Blumund with us?
Huh?
It'd be awfully sad to say goodbye here.
（エレン）
ここで さよならなんて寂しいです
（シズ）
あなたたちは いい冒険者だよ
You're all exceptional adventurers.
一緒に冒険できたら
どれほど楽しいだろうと思う
I'm sure it would be lots
of fun adventuring with you.
だったら…
Well, then...
ここまで旅ができて
やっぱり仲間って いいと思えた
Traveling together has shown me
how nice it is to be part of a group.
最後の旅が あなたたちとで
本当によかったと思っている
I'm truly grateful my last journey
was made with all of you.
シズさん 最後って…
Shizu, what do you mean by "last"?
もう うん十年も生きててね
見た目ほど若くないから
I've been around for decades, you know.
I'm not as young as I look.
は？　あっ な… なんだ 冗談か
Huh? O-Oh, you were just joking!
驚かさないでよ もう〜
Gosh, don't scare me like that!
Ah, here they come.
（リグル）おっ 来た来た
Sorry for the wait!
（エレン）お待たせ〜
（ギド）待ちくたびれたでやんすよ
Oh, we waited, all right.
Jeez, why do women take so long to get ready?
（カバル）
ったく… 女は支度が遅(おせ)えよな
シズさん？
Shizu?
（リムル）ん？
（リグルド）どうかしましたかな？
Is something wrong?
（シズ）うっ！　そんな… もう…
Not... again...
シズさん？
Shizu?
おい どうした？
Hey, what's wrong with you?
シズさん！
Shizu!
Shizu! Shizu!
シズさん！　シズさん！
（リムル）おっと！
あ… おい 大丈夫か？
Hey! Is everyone okay?
なんだよ これ！
危険手当 上乗せしてもらうぜ
What the hell is this?
We charge extra for hazard pay, you know!
（ギド）
だから！　それは
フューズの旦那に言うでやんすよ
You should be telling Fuze that!
Shizu! Shizu!
シズさん！　シズさ〜ん！
Shizu... Shizue Izawa?
シズ… シズエ･イザワ？
Huh?
（エレン）え？
（ギド）シズエ･イザワって…
Isn't Shizue Izawa...
...the Conqueror of Flames?!
（カバル）爆炎の支配者か？
Y-You mean the hero of the
guild from about 50 years ago?!
（エレン）
そ… それって
50年くらい前 活躍したっていう
ギルドの英雄よね？
シズさんが？
Shizu is her?
爆炎の…
The Conqueror of...
Wasn't she retired already?
もう 引退してんじゃ
なかったのか！
Rigurd, Rigur.
（リムル）リグルド！　リグル！
Evacuate the others.
（リムル）みんなを避難させろ
（リグルド）しかし…
（リグル）リムル様！
But...
Great Rimuru...
That's an order.
（リムル）命令だ
（リグルド）ははっ！　承りました
Yes, sir! As you wish!
（リムル）いるな？　ランガ
Are you there, Ranga?
Right here, Master.
（ランガ）我が主(あるじ)よ ここに
（リムル）始まったら頼む
Once it starts, you're up.
Of course!
炎の精霊… イフリート！
The fire spirit, Ifrit...
間違いないでやす
シズさんは…
There's no mistake, then. Shizu is...
伝説の英雄 爆炎の支配者…
...the legendary hero,
the Conqueror of Flames.
あ… あんなの どうやっても
勝てないんですけど？
Th-There's no way we can win
if we have to fight that!
Not a chance. We're going to die here.
無理でやす…
あっしらは ここで死ぬんでやす
短い人生だったでやんすねえ
My life was so short...
（エレン）きゃあ！
Damn it! We just built all that!
（リムル）
ちくしょう！　せっかく
作ったばかりだっていうのに
（カバル）うう…
（エレン）いった〜い
Ouch...
You guys need to get out of here!
（リムル）
お前たちも さっさと逃げろ！
We can't do that.
（カバル）
そんなわけにはいかねえよ
あの人が なんで殺意を
むき出しにしてんのか知らねえが…
I don't know why she's
suddenly out for blood...
俺たちの仲間でやすよ！
But she's one of us!
We can't just leave her!
ほっとけないわ！
All right. Just be careful.
（リムル）
そうか… 気をつけろよ！
They're really nice guys.
（リムル）
いいヤツらじゃないか
（カバル）
ハハ… まさか過去の英雄と
戦う日が来ようとはね
Never thought I'd see the day
when I'd fight a legendary hero.
（ギド）
人生 何が起こるか分かりやせんね
You never know what's
going to happen in life.
Let's go!
（リムル）いくぞ！
Hey! What is it you want?
（リムル）
おい！　お前の目的は何だ？
Water Blade!
水刃(すいじん)！
Yeah, I should've expected that.
まっ そりゃそうだよな
Icicle Lance!
（エレン）アイシクルランス！
（リムル）ん？
（サラマンダー）グアア！
（リムル）おい 大丈夫なのか？
Hey, you doing okay?
Just leave this to us!
（エレン）任せてくださいよ！
こっちだってね
命張って 冒険者やってるんです！
We've put our lives on the line
to be adventurers, you know!
おいおい 勘弁してくれよ
リーダーは俺だっての
Hey, gimme a break.
I'm the leader, remember?
まっ しょうがねえ
Well, whatever.
１匹は
俺たちが受け持った！
We've got the first one!
一蓮托生(いちれんたくしょう)ってやつでさあ！
We're all in the same boat, as they say!
（リムル）
じゃあ 任せる
だが 無理はするなよ！
I'll leave you to it, then.
But don't overdo it.
Whoa!
おっと！
Ranga!
ランガ！
Yes!
（リムル）ランガ 来るぞ
Ranga, here they come!
お前は回避に専念しろ
攻撃は俺がする
Just concentrate on evading
them! I'll do the attacking!
（ランガ）心得ました！
Understood!
あのイフリートの前に
We need to take care of those
guys before we can face Ifrit.
あいつらだな
What to do? My Water Blade
will just evaporate...
どうする？
水刃は蒸発してしまうが…
（リムル）
俺の胃袋に入っている大量の水を
But what if I shoot all the water
in my belly toward them at once?
一気にぶっかけるのは
どうだろう？
Answer.
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
解(かい)…
Answer
Expulsion of great amounts
of water is possible.
Expulsion of
great amounts of water
is possible
When it makes contact with a Salamander,
（大賢者）
サラマンダーとの接触により
水蒸気爆発が生じます
it will cause an explosion of steam.
Take this action?
（リムル）
水蒸気爆発！
それでサラマンダーは消滅するか？
An explosion of steam?
Will that destroy the Salamanders?
It is possible.
（大賢者）可能です
（リムル）おお！
However, the force of the blast may
destroy the surrounding area, as well.
（大賢者）
ただし 爆発の威力で
この辺り一帯も吹き飛ぶでしょう
Well, what's the point in that, then?!
（リムル）アホか！　意味ねえだろ
（サラマンダー）グガア！
Icicle Lance!
アイシクルランス！
グガアアア！
Her attack is working, isn't it?
（リムル）
あの攻撃 効いてるんじゃね？
（大賢者）
魔法攻撃は精霊に対して有効です
Magic attacks are effective against spirits.
（リムル）てことは…
Which means...
Ranga!
（リムル）ランガ！
（ランガ）はっ！
Yes!
Eren! Fire that attack at me!
（リムル）
エレン！
それ 俺に向けて撃ってくれ！
What?! Um, I don't know if I can...
はえっ？
えっと そんなこと言われても…
Just do it! Hurry!
（リムル）頼む！　早く！
Don't complain to me later!
（エレン）
あとで
文句 言わないでくださいよ！
Icicle Lance!
アイシクルラ〜ンス！
What?! My magic...
うえ〜！　私の魔法が…
Notice.
Notice
Analysis of Icicle Lance successful.
（大賢者）
アイシクルランスの解析に
成功しました
Analysis
Successful
All right!
（リムル）よし！
Icicle Shotgun!
（リムル）アイシクルショット！
Yes!
（リムル）よし！
I'll get that one, too—
（リムル）そいつも 俺が…
It's gonna blow itself up!
（カバル）こいつ 自爆を…
（カバル･ギド）ぐわあああ！
（エレン）きゃあああ！
Hey! Are you o—
（リムル）おい！　大丈夫…
Nope, they're not...
じゃないな
（カバル）うっ うぐ…
（リムル）
ランガ この３人を安全な場所へ
Ranga, get these three someplace safe.
（ランガ）しかし…
（リムル）行け！
But...
Go!
（ランガ）
はっ！　仰せのままに…
ご武運を
As you command, Master.
Please be well.
Don't worry.
（リムル）安心しろ
I'll take down Ifrit.
イフリートは俺が倒す
Okay, now we can fight without holding back.
（リムル）
さてと…
これで 心おきなく戦えるな
Take this! Icicle Shotgun!
くらえ！　アイシクルショット！
（リムル）
いける！
It's gonna work!
Master...
（ランガ）我が主…
（リムル）ぐわあああ！
（リムル）
ああ…
もっと やりようがあった気がする
There should've been
something else I could do!
I can't believe I fell into the enemy's trap!
敵の思惑どおり
罠(わな)にはまったなんて最悪だ〜！
Instead of talking about seals,
I should've hit them with Black Lightning!
封印とか言わないで
黒稲妻(くろいなずま)をぶち込んでおけば…
And after I was just reincarnated
here as a slime!
せっかくスライムに転生したのに
Is this really the end?!
ここまでか〜！
It was a short life...
短い人生… いや スライム生だった
rather, a short slife.
Actually, I don't seem
to be taking much damage.
ていうか
ダメージが なかなか来ないな？
How long is it gonna take?
てか 遅すぎない？
じらしプレイ？
Is this some kind of tease?
Answer.
Answer
As Previously Stated
Thermal Fluctuation Resistance
Due to "Thermal Fluctuation Resistance,"
（大賢者）
“熱変動耐性”の効果により…
fire attacks are being
automatically nullified.
Fire attacks are being
Ah.
（大賢者）
ハア…
Sigh...
Hey, why do you sound exasperated?!
（リムル）なんか あきれてない？
まあいい
炎が無効化できるのであれば…
Oh, well. If I can nullify fire attacks,
this'll be easy mode!
楽勝モードだ！
It's all good!
結果オーライ！　いや 全て…
In fact, everything is...
according to plan!
計画どおり
Did you just do something to me?
（リムル）今 何かしたのか？
I underestimated you, but not as
much as you underestimated me.
（リムル）
俺も お前のことをナメていたが
お前も 俺をナメ過ぎだったな
My turn.
俺のターンだ
Use unique skill "Predator"?
（大賢者）
ユニークスキル“捕食者”を
使用しますか？
（リムル）イエス！
Yes!
Shizu-san!
シズさん！
（ヴェルドラ）
観念せよ イフリート
Give up, Ifrit.
（ヴェルドラ）
貴様に この空間は破れん
You cannot break out of this place.
You are no match for Rimuru.
（ヴェルドラ）
貴様のかなう相手ではないわ
He is my sworn friend!
リムルは我の盟友ぞ！
I am the Storm Dragon, Veldora Tempest.
我は
暴風竜ヴェルドラ･テンペスト
It would be my pleasure to face you.
心ゆくまで相手をしてやろう
ハッハッハッハ！
Next time, "Inherited Will."
（大賢者）
次回「受け継がれる想(おも)い」
Inherited Will